Alexandra Huang

alexandra [dot] huang [at] gmail [dot] com

About Me

I'm a product designer/UX researcher who believes in understanding how people think, behave, and act in order to inform the design of products and systems that improve quality of life, from the smallest interactions with apps and websites to overall experiences with products and environments.

Education

M.S. in Human Factors and Ergonomics

GPA: 4.0

SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERSITY

Aug. 2018 - Dec. 2020

Sept. 2012 - Jun. 2016

· Relevant Coursework: Interaction Design I & II, User Research and Usability Testing, Human Factors/Ergonomics, Human Computer Interaction, Engineering Psychology

B.S. in Cognitive Science with Specialization in Human Computer Interaction **Minor in Computer Science**

Graduated Cum Laude, GPA: 3.756

• Relevant Coursework: HCI Programming Studio, Practicum in Prof. Web Design, Cognitive Design Studio, Cognitive Ethnography

Experience _____

University of California, San Diego

Product Design Intern San Mateo, CA

May 2019 - July 2019

- Led the research and design as the sole product designer on two projects on the Security and Privacy Team
- Conducted usability testing to discover problems with the SprintComplete.com breach check results page and test the redesign
- Worked with developers to implement the new website design via the prototype in Zeplin
- Designed and tested a series of mobile app screens (iOS and Android) on a new recovery feature for the Complete Security app

Electronics Technician II San Jose, CA

- WESTERN DIGITAL Jun. 2018 - Jun. 2019 Ran measurements of hard drive heads for reliability testing
- Ran data reduction scripts to generate reports

Proiects_

Chegg Gamification Project for Interaction Design II at SJSU

Link to project on portfolio

Nov. 2019 - Dec. 2019

May 2019 - Jul. 2019

DESIGN AND RESEARCH

· Worked in a team of two to design a gamified experience using Chegg's primary product, Chegg Study

- · Built a prototype to encourage use of three Chegg products and facilitate group work among Chegg users
 - Designed and prototyped in Axure

Asurion, Security and Privacy Team

Link to project 1 on portfolio

- (1) Researched, redesigned, and tested the Complete Security breach check results page, doubling conversion from 24.5% to 47.7%
- (2) Designed and tested a new feature for the Sprint Complete Security mobile app to implement a master keyphrase recovery solution

Designed in Sketch, prototyped in Invision, tested with UserTesting

Sunnyside Up Link to Invision prototype **IDEATION AND RESEARCH** Nov. 2018 - Jan. 2019

• Created a mobile app prototype in a team of four designed to help opioid addicts to recover from addiction

- Winner of the 2019 HFES Health Care Symposium Student Design Competition
 - Made with Sketch and Invision

Skills

UX/Design Tools Sketch, Invision, Axure, UserTesting, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap **CS/Programming** Java, Python, MATLAB, R, SQL, Git, Eclipse, Sublime

Awards & Extracurriculars _____

Mar. 2019	HFES Health Care Symposium Student Design Competition Winner , SJSU	San Jose, CA
2018 - present	Human Factors and Ergonomics Society , SJSU	San Jose, CA
2015 - present	Phi Beta Kappa member. Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society, UCSD Chapter	La Jolla. CA